This lady walks to The Synagogue Church of All Nations aided by her mother.
You can see from the looks on
her face that she is in excruciating pain.
Without the use of the lumbar corset around her waist,
carrying out daily activities will be very difficult.
IF YOU DON'T BELIEVE IN MIRACLES, WATCH THIS... !!!
Having moved from one place to another without a solution to this problem,
she has come to The Synagogue Church Of All Nations, believing that there is never a sickness
Jesus Christ cannot heal and never a disease He cannot cure.
These are medical reports from the hospital,
stating the level at which her discs have been damaged.
She has come with a problem of difficulty in walking due to prolapsed disc and lumbar sacralization.
The X-ray next to her further
explains the severity of the problem.
She uses a lumbar corset to support herself.
She has had this problem for the past two years.
This is the lumbar corset which she uses to support herself
in order to hold her spine in place to prevent further damage.
IF YOU DON'T BELIEVE IN MIRACLES, WATCH THIS... !!!
Welcome to The Synagogue Church Of All Nations.
Please tell us your name and where you're from.
My name is Tayo Akhamie. I'm from Nigeria.
What are you doing for a living, Ma?
I'm a legal practitioner, but I had to defer my PhD studies.
I was going for International Diplomacy and Human Relations for my PhD.
Madam, what is the problem that brought you here today?
The problem that brought me here today is difficulty in walking
due to prolapsed disc and lumbar sacralization of the spine.
As a result, I'm using a lumbar corset.
For how long have you been having this problem?
For two years.
How has this problem affected your life, Madam?
It has affected me a whole lot. I cannot walk without assistance,
I had to resign from my job. I get assistance in bathing and changing
and it has made my life miserable.
I cannot breathe very well. I usually faint because of the pain
and the nerves are affected.
As a result, I had to stop my PhD because I cannot read, understand and focus.
OK, Madam. So where have you been in search of solution for this problem?
I've been in Scotland, Germany, England and in California - no solution.
OK. We can see an X-ray next to you.
Could you please explain the X-ray.
What is it all about?
This X-ray is all about my spine,
One concentrates on the lumbar spine which is turned around.
It is somewhere here.
And that is why it is called the 'sacralization'.
'Sacralization' means fully turned around and it no longer becomes the disc it was.
You can't identify this.
The other X-ray is the one that passes through my chest and up.
I also have a prolapsed disc on this one.
It has affected my body and I also have trapped nerves in between my discs.
As a result of that, it has affected all my organs.
My organs are very challenged and out of 100%, my organs are functioning at 41%.
My muscle tone and balance is also very challenged and is functioning at 44% out of 100%.
As a result, if you pinch me with a needle or insert something through my skin,
I rarely feel the pain.
We can see a lumbar corset. Could you please tell us more about it, Madam.
The lumbar corset is used to support my lumbar spine so that it can be in alignment
because I also have misalignment of the spine
because the muscles around my spine are degenerating very fast.
When I stand, my muscle cannot
hold the spine in place and then it shifts
and causes the nerves to be trapped in-between my spine.
You mean, without this lumbar corset, you cannot walk?
No, without this lumbar corset, I cannot walk or sit.
Out of the 24 vertebrates, I have only six functioning a little bit.
As you can see on this diagram,
this was gotten from a recent machine.
It got this from a recent machine that was brought from NASA.
This machine is only being used for astronauts before they go to space
and when they come back.
This diagram depicts the nerves that are being affected.
My muscles and tone balance are very challenged.
I can barely stand or walk straight.
I barely have the strength to carry myself because my muscles are extremely weak.
I have done operations, I have done facet injections injected in my spine but all to no avail.
That was why I came here.
I believe that I will get healed of all my pains and infirmities, in Jesus' name.
Amen. We believe with you that Jesus Christ will heal you
for the salvation of your soul, in Jesus name.
Amen.
HEALING TIME
Here is Prophet T.B. Joshua ministering prayers to the people
who have come to The Synagogue, Church Of All Nations prayer line.
As he does, healing, deliverance
and all of God's blessings are released on them,
uprooting whatever that is not of God in their lives.
Man of God, help me!
Man of God, help my daughter! Please help me!
Please, Man of God, help me!
I have lumbar sacralization of the spine.
Man of God, help me.
As a result of this, I have trapped discs in-between my spine
I suffer from insomnia, I have to take drugs to sleep.
Man of God, please help me!
I have gastritis. Man of God, please help me.
I have pneumonia as a result of this. Man of God, please help me.
Please, I can't walk. Man of God, help me.
I've been to everywhere to no avail.
Man of God, please help me.
I'm dying gradually. Please help me.
Man of God, please help my daughter.
She cannot sleep well, she cannot sit for the past two years.
Severally, she tried to kill herself.
Please help me, Man of God. I can't do anything on my own.
My organs are gradually dying. Out of 100%, my organs are only functioning 41%.
My muscle and tone balance is very low; it is life threatening.
Out of 100%, only 44% are functioning.
I can't do anything on my own, I can't reason well.
I'm a lawyer but I can't work; I can't practice; I can't represent people in court.
I deferred my PhD because of this; please, help me!
Please, I have difficulty walking.
Please, Man of God, help me.
I have lumbar sacralization of the spine.
Come on.
Healing In Jesus' Name
Thank You, Jesus, for healing my daughter! Thank You, Lord!
Healed In Jesus' Name
Thank You, Jesus, I can walk!
I'm healed! Thank You, Jesus!
I'm healed! I can walk! Thank You, Jesus!
I am free! Thank You, Jesus!
My daughter is healed!
Thank You, Jesus! Thank You, Lord!
After her healing from difficulty in walking due to a prolapsed disc and lumbar sacralization,
Miss Tayo Akhamie came back to The Synagogue Church Of All Nations
the next service day to share her wonderful testimony to the glory of God.
On the left, you can see how she came to The Synagogue Church Of All Nations
in excruciating pain and barely
able to walk unassisted by her mother.
But today, Miss Tayo is a different
person.
With a vibrant smile, she can now freely move around pain-free.
Let's listen to her.
TESTIMONY TIME
Emmanuel!
(God With Us - Matthew 1:23)
Children of God, shout 'Emmanuel'!
My name is Akhamie Tayo.
I am a legal practitioner and I was about to start my PhD before I had this problem
which brought me to The Synagogue Church Of All Nations.
It all started two years back in Aberdeen, Scotland.
I travelled on an extensive trip and when I got back, I had a slight headache.
I prayed and went to bed.
I got up with excruciating pain and
went to shower.
Walking to the bathroom. I took three to four steps; then, I stopped.
I got stuck and didn't know what I was doing.
I couldn't move my legs or my arms; I was sweating profusely and shaking.
I could not communicate with my mouth, only with my eyes.
I was lucky that my friend was around to help me.
She said, "Toya, if you cannot communicate, blink your eyes for me.
When I ask you about the problem, if it is 'yes', blink once and 'no' blink twice".
That was how I could communicate before the ambulance came.
Thereafter, I was in the hospital, and it grew worse.
They tried all sorts of tests and the case was getting worse.
For over a month, I was placed on constant acupuncture,
every morning and evening but it didn't work.
Besides that, I always had steroids injected into my spine.
As time went on, I was told that surgery would be my only way out
but professional advice was that I was too young to have that surgery performed.
As a result of that, I had a misalignment of the spine from my axis to my coccyx,
which is the spine underneath my skull down to my tailbone.
This misalignment caused the nerves to be pressed in-between my spine.
As a result, all my organs in my body were affected.
Out of 100%, my muscle and tone balance only worked 44%.
Out of 100%, my hormones and organs only worked 41%.
In the vertebra, you will find 24 nerves.
Out of 24, I only had 6 functioning.
The nerve that passes through the axis
which is the one that holds the neck and the skull was severely damaged.
As a result, you could see the damage throughout -
from my skin, nails and hair loss, to all the essential organs in my body.
I was dying slowly.
I realized that there was no cure for this and the pain kept occurring.
I was too sore to go for physiotherapy and I could not really do anything.
I travelled from one place to another but at the end of the day,
I found out that the only solution was God - Jesus Christ.
That was why I came here.
When I came, I was fixed on the prayer line and the anointed man of God,
Prophet T.B. Joshua, stretched his hand forward and prayed for me.
Instantly, I fell to the ground.
I didn't know where I was and for a moment, I was oblivious
of what was happening around me physically.
The only thing I could hear where little voices but I could not see anybody.
I didn't know where I was.
In my mind I started fighting. I thought I was hallucinating.
I was thinking, "What is happening? Am I alone in the church?"
I couldn't see or hear anything,
Then, I heard a voice inside saying, "Get up! You are healed!
You are healed, in the name of Jesus!
You can do all things through Christ Jesus who strengthens you".
I got up. Instantaneously, I had no pain and I found myself walking.
Day by day, I've been getting stronger and stronger and stronger.
Now I'm free! This is my first time standing.
Before I couldn't sit down for one minute; I couldn't sit straight.
Now, I can sit for hours, I can stand, turn and twirl.
You can see God is wonderful.
I can squat. God is wonderful; praise God!
My name is John Akhamie.
I'm the father of Tayo - my last born.
She was preparing for her PhD program
when I received a telephone call from Scotland, precisely Aberdeen,
that my daughter was sick, bedridden, had been admitted
and that it was a very serious case.
She had a problem with her spine and needed urgent surgery
but they were afraid because of her age.
There was just a 50/50 chance of her surviving that type of surgery.
That it could lead to a total collapse of the nervous system or sudden death.
Because of that, they decided to use alternative methods -
giving her pain-relieving tablets and steroid injections but there was no response.
From there, she went to other parts of Europe.
In London, she was also admitted but there was no solution.
From there, we flew her to the United States, California, for the same problem
but there was no solution.
The doctors emphatically said that there was no solution
other than the surgery they did not advise.
That we should be patient and watch.
It was then that I asked my mother for the way out.
She said that she believed the way out was to come to The SCOAN.
I said that she was in the US and asked how she could take a flight to Nigeria.
She was merely given a lumbar corset to support her spine.
My wife sent the Anointing Water to one of my daughters in Los Angeles.
She ministered the Anointing Water on her and she regained some strength.
Then, she came back to Nigeria.
My reaction when I could not recognize my daughter was that I wept.
By that time, deformity had set in; she developed a hunchback
and the bottom of her backbone was curved.
In fact, she was very skinny and looking sickly.
She could not support herself.
She would lie down and couldn't get up unless we sat her up.
That was the situation.
My wife decided to bring her to The SCOAN.
When they eventually came back in the night, I heard noise downstairs.
My daughter was shouting and calling my name, "Daddy, I am healed!"
She ran upstairs and was jumping.
She was jumping up and down; she took my hands and was taking me round.
I said, "Is this my daughter?" I could not believe it.
She opened her apparel and I could see that the hunchback had disappeared.
Her backbone had straightened as she used to be in those days.
I give glory to God. To me, this is the biggest miracle in my life.
While she was undergoing this pain, I was also feeling the pain.
I would go to my bedroom and quietly shed tears.
Occasionally, she would call me and say, "Daddy, I know you have tried for me,
and mummy has also tried. I want to go".
I would say, "Where are you going to? Don't say that again".
"I want to go." - she kept repeating that.
Now, she is very strong and since that day, she is getting stronger and stronger.
I also noticed that all the rashes on her skin,
and the veins that were coming out disappeared.
She now has a good skin.
This shows that every part of her body has been healed.
I give glory to God.
Since that day, every morning my daughter wakes me up
and leads me on a jog around the compound.
She dances and can twirl around 360 degrees; this she could not do before.
She can jump up and is very healthy as if she was never sick before.
There is another aspect to it.
When she was coming back from the U.S., the doctors were told
that she was bringing the X-rays as a requirement to come to The SCOAN.
They said that the sickness could not be cured and that we were just wasting our time.
They said that if she received her healing, they would be interested.
IF YOU DON'T BELIEVE IN MIRACLES, WATCH THIS... !!!
I thank God Almighty for His grace in the life of Prophet T.B. Joshua.
This singular incident is a milestone in my life.
It is an incident I will never forget in my life.
It has increased my faith in the Lord.
For the whole world to know, Prophet T.B. Joshua has super grace in his life.
It is just unexplainable; it is a mystery.
My daughter went around the whole world to the best hospitals.
It was a sickness they said could not be cured and that it was impossible.
She came to The SCOAN and in a split second, she was healed.
Thank you.
Let's now go back to what actually happened to the little girl and the father.
What happened to you when I drew you down suddenly?
You were here for healing, for prayer
and you expected me to lay hand
and begin to say, "I rebuke, in Jesus' name!",
"I heal you, in Jesus' name!"
"I bind that sickness, in Jesus' name!"
So that you too would be saying, "Amen!"
But instead of that, I went towards you and dragged you on the floor.
What came upon you when I dragged you as if I was fighting you?
Okay. The first impression was that I heard you shout and say, "Get up!"
I was thinking, "I can't get up, of course".
I was wondering if I was shameful or bad that he forced me to get up.
I thought, "He is very angry; I must be a terrible sinner".
That was what that spirit that caused that terrible pain deserved!
I was not fighting her; I was fighting that spirit that caused her pain.
I was not trying to be hard on her but on the spirit that caused her pain.
I was very aggressive towards that spirit because I was not happy.
How can a young lady trying to get her PhD be arrested, be caged with this stupid pain?
I was looking at this spirit and wondering, "What is wrong with you, you evil spirit?
Why should you do that?"
I was fighting that spirit.
IF YOU DON'T BELIEVE IN MIRACLES, WATCH THIS... !!!
So it was unnecessary to now give my attention to that evil spirit.
I did not want to give attention to the spirit; rather I wanted to embarrass this spirit.
Hallelujah.
God heals, we treat.
We all - medical doctors, physicians, whatever - treat while God heals.
That's true, sir.
Thank you. What can you say to the world with your age?
Before I give my advice, please I would like to shed some light on the items on the board.
This is one of the last tests I went for.
This machine is one of its kind; it just came out and it is from NASA.
They use this machine for astronauts before they go into space
and when they come back.
It is to detect the cause of the problem even before it starts to manifest.
I brought this because it is easily explainable.
This is how the spine is.
You have from the atlas to the coccyx which is the tail of the spine.
The atlas holds the skull on the neck.
This is all the way down to the coccyx in your pelvic.
This diagram explains this.
If you take a closer look at this vertebra, you will see some of the vertebra underlined.
These were all the vertebra I had problems with.
All these nerves passing through this vertebra, I had problems with.
Out of 24, I only had 6 functioning.
If you take a look at 1C, you will see the areas controlled by the nerves
and you can see what the problem was: blood supply to the head, pituitary gland,
scalp, bones of the face, brain, inner and middle ear, sympathetic nervous system.
And these would be the possible effects of the malfunction:
headache, neurosis, insomnia, head colds, high blood pressure,
migraine headaches and so on and so forth.
If you take a good look down, you will see that
I had a problem in almost all the vertebra and I had a complex problem.
Now, if you come here, this is the EMC machine. I don't know what it is really called.
It's so advanced. This machine detects the nerves that have a problem.
If you come down here, you will see that this is the overall graph.
Here is danger, which is my axis and now if you come here, you will see C1, C1, C3, C3.
You see that it is black. If you come here, you will see that this is C3.
And this is what - cheeks, outer ear,
face bones, teeth, trifacial nerve.
The black means it is damaged - beyond repair -
and that shows how bad my body was.
If you could see my spine, it was almost like a Christmas tree
because you could see numerous colors.
The normal spine is supposed to be like this - just plain and healthy.
But I had colors everywhere - measuring the temperature of the pain
and the extent of the damage in my body.
To be honest, when I had the tests done,
there were other Asian doctors coming to the room to look at me.
Why? Because they had a slight argument
when they saw the various reports that came from one person.
They argued and said, "No, it's not possible that one person can have all this!
I'm sure you must be mistaken. Maybe, you made a mistake somewhere.
It can't be from one person".
The doctor then replied that it was from one person.
Funny enough, when they came to look at me, they said, "Hi" and I responded.
They actually came to see if I was assisted by a form of stretcher or something.
They couldn't believe that I could reason well.
But after the man of God prayed for me, you see that all these disappeared.
I can turn, squat, twirl, I am so happy. I can jump and do much more.
I'm so happy! Praise God!
Hallelujah. You have listened to our sister.
Look at the old picture and the present picture. She looked old in the former picture.
No one could believe that she is a young girl.
At that former picture, she looked very, very old.
But now, she looks very young and just one week healing.
By the next two months, I think she will be a 15 years-old baby.
Hallelujah. This is to tell you that when you are healed,
you are healed in your fluids, in your blood and in your muscles.
The cause of that sickness is in the blood.
So not only just making you walk but right to the root of that problem.
That is the fluid, the blood because that sickness is in the blood.
That is causing the face to deform.
So the Spirit of God has to go there straight and get it uprooted from the blood.
Not just to make her walk. If it is just to make her walk, it would be temporary healing.
Later, the thing will still fall down because it's in the blood.
So that is the healing of God. When you are healed, you are healed perpetually.
And indeed, you are healed.
Thank You, Lord.
What a radical transformation within less than a week.
On the left, we can see how deformed her waist was due to the spinal problem
and having to wear a very tight lumbar corset.
Her face was also very pale and full of pimples.
But instantly after her healing, her skin color returned to normal,
leaving her with a now glowing skin,
proving the complete internal healing she received in Jesus' name.
Not only was her spinal cord restored, but her blood and every organ of our body
has been renewed by the Master Healer, Jesus Christ.
Glory be to God.
We believe you have been inspired by the clip you have just watched.
Click here to subscribe to witness more of God's power at work in our generation today,
and stay up-to-date with the latest prophecies, deliverances,
sermons and testimonies from The SCOAN.
Emmanuel TV - Changing lives, Changing nations and Changing the world.
TT: Lizz Ndungu
RV: Mel Flowers 08/07/2018